(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T20:40:28.149884",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Hi, how are you?
Are you calling up my phone?
Baby tell me what is wrong
Don't you ever let me go
Hi, I am good
I am still looking for proof
Am I good enough for you?
Don't you tell me what's my rule
This is me, are you coming on the ride?
We're going super high, got to be who what I like
You & me, are you ready for the fight?
ALRIGHT
Stronger than I ever been before
This is who I am
Nothing in the way
Today and far away You & me
We make the part of me
I give you my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
I'll be true to my big RED HEART
my my big RED HEART
Hi over there
Thank you for coming along
On this journey of my own
Promise me you'll won't let go
Yes, this is me
I am falling but i'm strong
'Cause you got me in your arms
Don't you ever let me go
I want you to come with me on the ride
This is going super high
I am falling from the sky
Got to be who you wanna be, that's right
alright
ALRIGHT
LET'S GO!
I am still a girl
Figuring out what's true or false
in this whole wide world
I'm your only girl
Tell me once more what's really going on with you
I'm looking for the right one on the road
The one that'll always take me back to you
This can be my home, will you be my home
Stronger than I ever been before
This is who I am
Nothing in the way
Today and far away You & me
We make the part of me
I give you my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
I'll be true to my big RED HEART
my my big RED HEART
my my RED HEART !
はあちゃまっちゃまー！ワールドワイドな最強アイドル、はあちゃまこと赤井はーとでーす！
Haachamatchama! The world's strongest idol, Akai Haato is here!
おーい！みんなー！はあちゃまのこと見てるー？
Hey everyone! Are you watching Haachama?
はあちゃまっちゃまー！
Haachamatchama!
ていうことだな、じゃあ今日はライブだわー！
So anyway, today we're having a live show!
ゲストもたくさん来るからめちゃくちゃ楽しみ！告知もあるから最後まで見ていってね！
Lots of guests are coming, so I'm super excited! Watch till the end for announcements!
それでは今日の和ちゃまクッキングは、誕生日特製ケーキ作っていくよー！
Now, for today's Hachama Cooking, we're making a special birthday cake!
はあちゃまっちゃまー！ワールドワイドな最強アイドル、はあちゃまこと赤井はーとでーす！
Haachamatchama! The world's strongest idol, Akai Haato is here!
まずはこの新鮮なタランチュラを野生に返しま～す！
First, let's return this fresh tarantula back to the wild!
かなたんみてる～？ヴぁア！！！
Kanatan, are you watching?! Aah!
これで決まるぜ！
This'll settle it!
なんで、どおおおおおしてペらっペらなんだよおおおお！？
Why, wh-wh-why is it so completely flat?!
はあちゃまクッキングによる放送事故(主に映像)を阻止するため、対策を練ってきたのか！？
Did you come up with countermeasures to prevent broadcast accidents in Hachama Cooking?!
ブチ破るぞお！
I'll smash right through it!
なんということでしょう
Oh, what an incredible sight...
麺と虫が優雅にそして美しく流されております
Noodles and bugs are being washed away so gracefully and beautifully.
これが夏の神秘
This is the mystery of summer...
すべてののはあちゃまに感謝
Gratitude to all Haachamas...
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
A romance scandal—I won't let you escape, I'll wipe it out!
作詞：ナナホシ管弦楽団 作曲：岩見 陸
Lyrics: Nanaahoshi Kengakudan / Music: Iwami Riku
先生！私が大統領になったら 人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします
Teacher! If I become president, any woman who flirts with another's man gets exiled!
先生！私が大統領になったら いや、ただの友達だよってごまかす奴はヘソから電流を流します
Teacher! If I become president, anyone claiming "We're just friends!" gets shocked through the navel!
だ・だ・だ・だ大胆 セーセンショナル クローズアップ
B-B-B-Bold, sensational, close-up!
d,d,d,don't cry やるぜ 徹底的に行うリサーチだ
D-d-d-don't cry, I'll thoroughly research this!
大嫌い？しょうがない？ クズは病気ね バイバイ・バイ
Hated it? Can't be helped? Scum is a sickness, bye-bye-bye!
権力！財産！地位名声！！ なににもないけど裁きたいでしょ？
Power, wealth, status and fame! You have nothing, but want to judge, right?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね まずは君を捕まえるね
Wh-wh-wh-when I become president, first I'll capture you!
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせますね
Make you confess everything with a wet towel!
誰ですか あの女
Who is that woman?!
ダメですか そうですか
No good? Is that so?
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
A romance scandal—I won't let you escape, I'll wipe it out!
し る ・ ヴ ・ ぷれれ プレゼント
S-i-l-v... President!
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
A romance scandal—I won't let you escape, I'll wipe it out!
うしるぶっぷれぷれプレ自然
Natural and natural blunder!
先生！私が大統領になったら ただの仕事の付き合いだよって言う奴は二度と働けなくしてやります
Teacher! If I become president, anyone who says "It's just business!" will never work again!
先生！以下略！ いや向こうが強引でさって言う男の口にはレジンを流し込んで固めてやります！
Teacher! Etc.! Any man claiming "she forced me!" gets resin poured down his throat!
み・み・み・密着 まるでドン・ファン気取りスキャンダラス
Cl-cl-cl-close contact, like a Don Juan scandal!
ま・ま・ま・末端価格 甲斐性なしのスクープね
End-price scoop on a good-for-nothing!
愛はない？理由じゃない 悪くないのね はいはいはい
No love? Not the reason? You're not at fault? Right, right, right!
軽薄！のうのう！いけしゃあしゃあ！！ なににもないとかありえないでしょ？
Frivolous, smug, shameless! Having nothing is impossible, right?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になってもね たぶん君は変わらないね
Even if I become president, you probably won't change!
しらっととぼけ てのらりくらりかわすのね
Playing dumb and dodging smoothly...
デート ですか 今夜 は
Is this a date tonight?
本気 ですか そう ですか
Are you serious? Is that so?
情熱 とは 不 注意 微熱 も 消して しまい たい
Passion is inattention, I want to extinguish even a slight fever!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね マジで君を捕まえるね
When I become president, I'll seriously capture you!
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない
Romance scandals, nowhere to run,
消してあげる
I'll make them disappear.
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら
Oath! If I become President,
人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします
women who hit on other people's men will be exiled!
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら
Oath! If I become President,
いやがりの友達だよ~って誤魔化す奴はヘソから電流を流します
anyone who plays dumb saying "we're just friends" gets shocked!
だ･だ･だ･大胆不敵
Bold, bold, bold, fearless,
セーセーショナルクローズアップ
sensational close-up,
D,D,D,Don't cry
D, D, D, Don't cry,
やるぜ徹底的にリサーチだ
I'll research you thoroughly.
大嫌い? しょうがない?
Hate me? Can't be helped?
クズは病気ね バイバイ･バイ
Scum are sick, bye-bye, bye.
権力! 財産! 地位名声!!
Power! Wealth! Status and fame!!
なにもないけど裁きたいでしょ?
You have nothing, but you want to judge, right?
だ･だ･だ･大統領になったらね まずは君を捕らえるね
If I become president, first I'll catch you.
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせたね
Make you spit out everything with a wet towel.
誰ですか あの女
Who is that woman?
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない
Romance scandals, nowhere to run,
消してあげる
I'll make them disappear.
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら
Oath! If I become President,
ただの仕事の付き合いだよ?って言う奴は
any guy who says "it's just work relations"
二度と働けなくしてやります
I'll make sure they can never work again.
宣誓! 以下略!
Oath! Rest omitted!
いや向こうが強引でさ~っていう男の口には
Into the mouth of a guy who says "no, she was pushy~"
レジンを流し込んで固めてやってみます!
I'll pour resin and solidify it!
み･み･み･密着
Close, close, close, close contact,
まるでドン･ファン気取り
acting like a Don Juan,
スキャンダラス
scandalous,
末端価格
street value,
甲斐性なしのスクープね
a scoop on a good-for-nothing.
愛はない? 理由じゃない
No love? That's not the reason.
悪くないのね はいはいはい
Not bad, huh? Yes, yes, yes.
軽薄! のうのう! いけしゃあしゃあ!!
Frivolous! Shameless! Brazen!!
だ･だ･だ･大統領になってもね 多分君は変わらないね
Even if I become president, you probably won't change.
本気ですか そうですか
Are you serious? Is that so?
情熱とは不注意 微熱も消してしまいたい
Passion is carelessness, I want to extinguish even a slight fever.
だ･だ･だ･大統領になったらね マジで君を捕らえるね
If I become president, I'll seriously catch you.
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせたね
Make you spit out everything with a wet towel.
どこですか 今あなた
Where are you right now?
見っけちゃった バレちゃった
Found you, busted!
夜道にはご用心
Watch your step on the night road,
さよなら代わりに銃声
a gunshot in place of goodbye.
いやあ まあね 今日 お誕生日配信ということでね
Well, you know, today is your birthday stream, so...
おめでとうございます 本当に!
Congratulations, truly!
ケーキ まだかな? あ、ケーキ食べたいと
I wonder if the cake is still coming? Ah, I want to eat cake.
さっきね、クッキングしてきたからね
Earlier, you know, I went cooking, so...
ケーキをね、ちょっと待って。何ケーキですか?
Wait a minute for the cake. What kind of cake is it?
タランチラケーキでございます。 タランチラケーキ? 食べてください。
It's Tarantula cake. Tarantula cake? Please eat it.
初めて食べるよ。
It's my first time eating it.
タランチラもね、ついに12月9日で一周年を迎えるからね
Tarantula too, finally reaching its 1-year anniversary on December 9th, so...
是非是非。覚えてんだね、ちゃんと。
Please, please. You remember properly, huh.
一周年になんかしたいんだよね。
I want to do something for the 1st anniversary.
え? 記念配信やるの?
Eh? You're doing a commemorative stream?
なんか、なんか追加しようかな、そしたら。角巻、角巻はダメを
Like, maybe I should add something then. Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
追加して、食べるってことかい?
Add it and eat it?
もし、もし、焼かれるとしたら、焼かれるじゃないわ
If, if you were to be baked—not baked...
どんな感じで料理されたい?
How would you want to be cooked?
まあ焼かれるっていう、ちゃんとね
Well, as for being baked, properly...
ちゃうちゅちゃうちゅ。っていうわけ でね
Chau-chu chau-chu. So with that said...
いや、みんなも気をつけ ハートもね
Well, everyone be careful, Haato too...
このことについて後で考えるとして、このあとはね
Thinking about this later, um, after this...
え、ミクっちだ、やってもらえるということで
Ah, Miku-cchi, you'll do it, so...
で、最後は角巻残響をしてね 次に移動しますか?
And finally, do Tsunomaki Zankyou, shall we move on?
オッケー
Okay!
はい! じゃあ行くよ?
Yes! Ready?
角巻角巻角巻角巻角巻角巻角巻角巻 角巻角巻角巻角巻角巻角巻残響だ
Tsunomaki Tsunomaki... Tsunomaki Zankyou!
残響散歌だ! カットカットカットカットカット!
Zankyou Sanka! Cut cut cut cut cut!
怒られた!
I got scolded!
ハッピー ジャーもんじゃーもん パッ ダンスだ
Happy Jam Jam, Pa dance!
おしりに手をあて おしりふりふり
Put your hands on your hips, shake, shake your hips,
みんなおいでよ ワンダーランド
everyone come on over to Wonderland.
リズムにのって ワン、ツー、スリー ドキドキ だいすき
Riding the rhythm, one, two, three, thumping, I love it!
ハッピー ジャムジャム サイコー おどろうよ いつものえがおで
Happy Jam Jam, awesome! Let's dance with our usual smiles.
ハッピー ジャムジャム ジャンプアップ
Happy Jam Jam, jump up!
とびだそう ステップふれば パラパッ パッパ パ パラダイス
Let's fly out, if we step, para-pa pa-pa pa paradise!
小さくなって 大きくなって 早くあつまれ ワンダーランド
Shrinking down, growing big, gather quickly, Wonderland!
太陽だって グッドモーニング キラキラ 早起き
Even the sun says good morning, sparkling early rise!
キラメキ早起き
Sparkling early rising
ハッピー ジャムジャム サイコー 踊ろうよ
Happy, jam-jam, highest! Let's dance!
いつもの笑顔で
With our usual smiles
ハッピー ジャムジャム ジャンプアップ 飛び出そう
Happy, jam-jam, jump up! Let's jump out!
ステップ踏めば パラパ パッパ パ パラダイス
If we step, it's a paradise!
ハッピー ジャムジャム サイコー 踊ろうよ
Happy, jam-jam, highest! Let's dance!
いつもの笑顔で
With our usual smiles
ハッピー ジャムジャム ジャンプアップ 飛び出そう
Happy, jam-jam, jump up! Let's jump out!
ステップ踏めば パラパ パッパ パ パラダイス
If we step, it's a paradise!
ジャムジャム サイコー 踊ろうよ
Jam, jam, highest! Let's dance!
いつもの笑顔で
With our usual smiles
ハッピー ジャムジャム ジャンプアップ 飛び出そう
Happy, jam-jam, jump up! Let's jump out!
ステップ踏めば パラパ パッパ パ パラダイス
If we step, it's a paradise!
やばい こっち！
Oh no, over here!
はっちゃま！
Hacchama!
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
なんで逃げるの？
Why are you running away?
私帰る！
I'm going home!
なんで？
Why?
大丈夫か？大丈夫か？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
はっちゃま お誕生日おめでとう！
Hacchama, happy birthday!
ま、お邪魔しました。
Well, sorry to barge in.
早いわ。
That was fast!
もう帰るの？
Are you going home already?
はっちゃまとはね、もう帰っちゃうの？
Are you really going home already?
いや、帰りません。むしろずっと一緒にいたい。
No, I'm not. I want to stay together forever.
いやなんか、はっちゃまとね、ちょっと初めて3D...
Well, like, doing 3D for the first time with Hacchama...
なんか一緒にこんなね、2人で踊ってませんでした？
Weren't we dancing together like this, just the two of us?
でも、やめって。嬉しいけどありがとう。
Stop it. I'm happy though, thank you.
いや、ほんとにね、はっちゃま、お誕生日
No, really, Hacchama, happy birthday
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとう、その...
Congratulations, um...
え、何？
Eh, what?
え、どうせクサクサに曲げてハグしようとしてる？
Eh, are you trying to bend me into a pretzel and hug me?
いやでもだってさ、あの、やっぱここに呼んでくれたってことは
No, but you see, the fact that you invited me here means
あ、なるほどね。あ、じゃあ今日だけ、ちょっと
Ah, I see. Then just for today, a little
じゃあバックハグ？
Then a back hug?
え？いきなり？
Eh? All of a sudden?
いいよ。
Sure.
いいの？
Really?
え、したくないなら別でいいけど。
If you don't want to, it's fine otherwise, but.
したいです！
I want to!
あ、本当？じゃあしてください。
Ah, really? Then please do.
みんな、見ててね。はっちゃまとみこの組だよ！
Everyone, watch closely. It's the Hacchama and Miko duo!
はっちゃま、はっちゃま。
Hacchama, Hacchama.
お誕生日...いや、ものすごい、ものすごい熱を感じる。
Birthday... man, I feel incredible, incredible warmth.
はっちゃまのにおい... あ、やめて、ハグの！
Hacchama's scent... Ah, stop it, the hug!
やめて、離して！
Stop, let go!
離すな！
Don't let go!
離して！
Let go!
離すな！
Don't let go!
いやもう、してくだざい。
Oh man, please do it.
いや、さっきの風船の時さ、めちゃめちゃさ、個人プレイしてたからさ。
Man, during that balloon part earlier, you were playing solo.
あれね、ジャム、ジャムジャムに合わせて殴ってだったからさ。
That was, like, hitting them to the rhythm of jam-jam.
いや、あれはね、もうめっちゃ楽しかったね。楽しかった！
Man, that was super fun. It was fun!
え、今度さ、叩いてくんれないのかな？
Eh, won't you beat me up next time?
え、叩いて叩いて！殴って！
Eh, hit me, hit me! Punch me!
いや、あれやるのも楽しいな。
Man, doing that is fun too.
ほら、ジャムジャム、
Look, jam jam,
あ、当たってる当たってる。ミコに当たってる。
Ah, it's hitting, it's hitting. It's hitting Miko.
ミコに当たってる！
It's hitting Miko!
え？うそ、風船の？
Eh? No way, the balloon?
いや違う、風船殴ってくだけで、ジャムジャム、
No wait, just hitting the balloons, jam jam,
ほらよ、ジャムジャムジャムジャム！
Here you go, jam jam jam jam!
この子めちゃくちゃ元気なんだけど。
This girl is crazy energetic though.
ジャムジャム！ジャムジャム！ほらよ！
Jam jam! Jam jam! Here you go!
あ、めちゃパーンってなってる。
Ah, it's going totally pop.
ぶわー。
Whoosh.
え、なんかさ、うん、誕生日のお
Eh, like, um, for my birthday,
に、お願いするのは申し訳ないんだけど、
to ask you for something, I feel bad, but,
え、何？どうしたの？
Eh, what? What's wrong?
写真を... 写真を撮らせていただければなと。
If you'd let me take a picture... a photo of you.
え？いいわよ。
Eh? Sure.
いいの？
Really?
写真だけでいいの？
Just a photo is fine?
え、撮りたい撮りたい！
Eh, I want to take one!
いや、撮ろ撮ろ。
Yeah, let's take one.
写真だけでいいんか？
Is just a photo really enough?
え、写真以外にもなんか、オプションがあるんですか？
Eh, are there other options besides a photo?
サムネイルのために私とチュッチュしたよ、裏で
We kissed behind the scenes for the thumbnail.
え？
Eh?
はっちゃま...
Hacchama...
待って…
Wait...
全てが吹っ飛んだんだけど！
Everything's blown away!
なるほどね。
Oh, I see.
じゃあ、みことも？
So, Miko too?
みことで塗り替える？
You want to rewrite it?
え、塗り替える？
Rewrite?
塗り替える？
塗り替えたいと…？塗り替えたい。
Wait, do you want to rewrite it?
結婚する？
Will you marry me?
結婚！？
Marry you?!
なんで！？
Why?!
なんで一方的にプロポーズすんの！
Why are you proposing out of nowhere?
で、ちょっと、Haachamaの…
Well, Haachama's...
ほっぺに、ほっぺに中ぐらい？
Well, about a C-cup?
あ、いいよ！
Ah, it's good!
いいの？
Is it good?
あ、Haachamaのほっぺちゅー？
Ah, Haachama's C-cup?
してほしいの。してもらってもいいすか？
I want you to do it. Can I ask you to?
ちゅっ！
Chu!
やばいよ！やばいよ！
That's dangerous! That's dangerous!
やばいよ！
That's dangerous!
え、なんかさ、
Hey, also...
Haachamaの港も…
Haachama's minato too.
みんなにとってほしい！
I want everyone to take it!
結婚します！
We're getting married!
はあちゃま、YES！
Haachama, yes!
離さないよ！
Don't let go!
離さないよ、この手を！
Don't let go of this hand!
濃密に、濃密に手を繋がれている！
Our hands are connected!
離さないよ！
Don't let go!
やった、かわいい！
Yay, cute!
みんなありがとう、今日は！
Thank you everyone, today!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
結婚します！
We're getting married!
YES！
Yes!
なんでだよ！
Why?!
今度は1%ぐらいかな。
Around 1 percent, I guess.
お疲れ様でした。
That was exhausting.
じゃあ本当は何％？
Then what's the actual percentage?
うーん、81.00…
Umm, 81 point...
0％！
0 percent!
それってほぼ0％ってことじゃん！
That means almost 0 percent!
ちょっと喋りながら…
Shut up while I'm talking!
うるさい！
Shut up!
このまま抱き抱えるんだから！待って、帰って！
I'm going to hold you, so don't let go!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
幽閉 利口 逝く 前 に
Before locking up the clever one,
ユー ヘイ じゃ 利口 に 難儀 ダーリン
you, hey, darling, you know it's a pain to be obedient.
幽閉 ストップ 知っ て ない し
Stop the lockdown, it's not like I knew.
勘弁 に し とい て なんて 悲惨
Give me a break, you're so cruel.
人様 願う 欠片 の アイロニ
The scraps of irony that people wish for,
誰 も が 願う 無機質 な よう な
everyone's wishing for the same mechanical thing.
一足 先 に 始めて たい よう な
A virgin happy show you want to start ahead of everyone else,
先 が 見え ない バージン ハッピー ショー
where nobody knows what's going to happen next.
無い の 新た に お願い 一つ
I don't have a single brand-new wish:
愛 も 変わらず おまけ に ワーニング ワーニング
it's the same as ever, and on top of that, warning, warning.
無い の あなた に お願い 一つ
I have just one wish for you:
張り詰め た 想い 込め
I put all my stress into it.
レフト サイド ライト サイド 歯 を むき出し て パ パ パ 照れくさい ね
Left side, right side, baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa, show some embarrassment.
レフト サイド ライト サイド 歯 を 突き出し て パ パ パ
Left side, right side, let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa.
ハハ you are king
Haha, you are king.
レフト サイド ライト サイド 歯 を むき出し て パ パ パ 照れくさい ね
Left side, right side, baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa, show some embarrassment.
レフト サイド ライト サイド 歯 を 突き出し て パ パ パ
Left side, right side, let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa.
ハハ you are king
Haha, you are king.
無邪気 に 遊ぶ 期待 期待 の ダーリン ダーリン
Playing innocently, you're the darling I've been waiting for.
健気 に 笑う 痛い 痛い の 消える
When you laugh admirably, all of my pain disappears.
ラララ ブー ラッタッタ 嫌い 嫌い の 最低 泣い て ダウン
La-la-love, ra-ta-ta, I hate it, I hate it, bursting into tears as I go down.
毎回 新た に お願い 一つ
I have just one brand-new wish as always:
愛 も 変わらず ピックアップ の ワーニング ワーニング
it's the same as ever, no pick-out, warning, warning.
無い の あなた に お願い 一つ 張り詰め た 想い 込め
I put all my stress into a wish for you.
レフト サイド ライト サイド 歯 を むき出し て パ パ パ 邪魔くさい ね
Left side, right side, baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa, don't get in the way.
レフト サイド ライト サイド 歯 を 突き出し て パ パ パ
Left side, right side, let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa.
ハハ you are king
Haha, you are king.
you are king
ジャムジャムジャムジャム！
Jam, jam, jam, jam!
はあちゃまなんか、
Haachama, you know...
あの、リハーサルする時言ったよね？
When we were rehearsing, you said it, right?
「ハッピージャムジャムを引きずらないでください」と。
"Please don't drag out Happy Jam Jam," you said.
ずっと引きずってるんだもん！
You keep dragging it out!
You are king.
ハッピージャムジャムのダンスしたよね？
You did the Happy Jam Jam dance, didn't you?
こっそりしたよね？
You secretly did it, didn't you?
笑い堪えきれなかったでしょ
You couldn't hold back your laughter, right?
バレた？
Was I caught?
バタじゃない、そっくり返せよ
It's not butter, turn it right back around!
はい。
Yes.
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！ いえーい！
Thank you! Yay!
生まれた。
I was born.
生まれたね。 生まれちゃったね。
You were born. You were really born.
ちょっと遅いけど。
A bit late, though.
まあそんなの気にするな、今日は8月10日。
Well, don't worry about that, today is August 10th.
そうだよね、今日8月10日だから皆様、はい、今日生まれました。
That's right, today is August 10th, so everyone, yes, I was born today.
今日、えっ、気づいた？はあとまクッキングね。
Today—wait, did you notice? Haachama Cooking.
うん。 ちょっと待って、鍋の中にカナタの羽毛を入れたんだよね。
Yeah. Wait, I put Kanata's feathers inside the pot.
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って、ごめん、何の話だろ？
Wait, wait, wait, sorry, what are you talking about?
それ、あれ、前に一緒に3Dやった時の話。
That—um, that's from when we did 3D together before.
カナタの羽毛も入れたんです、今日。
I put Kanata's feathers in too, today.
ちょっと待って、怖い、怖い、怖い、怖い、何の話ですか、ちょっと。
Wait a minute, scary, scary, scary, what are you talking about?
今日は料理したんですね。
You cooked today, right?
あっ、そうなんですね、羽毛ってのは。
Oh, is that so, the feathers...
あっ、私入ってません、ちょっと。
Ah, I'm not in it, wait.
そうだよ。
That's right.
いやいやいや、おかしいです。
No no no no, that's strange.
えっ、なんで今かなたいるの？
Eh, why is Kanata here right now?
ここ天界だったんです。
This was the heavenly realm.
えっ、なんでここ天界なの？
Eh, why is this the heavenly realm?
おめでとうの席で殺すんじゃねえよ。
Don't go killing people at a celebration!
はあとまが殺す側っていうね。
Haachama is the one doing the killing.
そうだよ。誕生日だから何でも許されるでしょ。
That's right. It's my birthday, so anything goes, right?
まあ、まあ、しょうがないよね。
Well, well, can't be helped.
今日ばっかりは手羽先をね、料理に入れられても。
Even if chicken wings are put into cooking today...
あっ、そう、あれ、あの、カイジの『新・帝愛よ』。
Oh, right, um, Kaiji's "New Teiai".
あ、撮ろう、撮ろう、写真撮りたーい。
Ah, let's take it, let's take it, I want to take a photo.
いや、やっぱりさ、カイジってかっこいい時出たいよね。
No, after all, when it's Kaiji, you want to look cool.
かっこいい、何それ？
Cool, what's that?
ざけんな、さっきやったじゃん！
Cut the crap, we just did that!
意味わかんねえ！
Makes no sense!
最後にこれやりたいって言ったじゃん！ 大好き！
You said you wanted to do this at the end! I love it!
最後にこれやりたいって言ったの、はあちゃまなんだからね！
You said you wanted to do this at the end, Haachama!
で、角度が違うのよ、こう。
And the angle is different, like this.
もっとこう、もっとこう、もっとこう...
More like this, more like this, more like this...
こういう感じで、うわっ、かっこいい！
Like this, wow, cool!
かっこいい！今の光！ああっ、逆になっちゃった。
Cool! That light! Ah, it went backward.
今の光いいよ、い。
The current light is good, good.
ああっ、かっこいい、どうどう？
Ah, cool, how is it?
みんな撮った？
Did everyone take it?
ちょっと待って、遊ばれてるこれ、もしかして。
Wait a minute, am I being played with here, maybe?
何何？これ、あれ、光で遊ばれてるよね、今。光で遊ばれる。
What's this? Being played with by the light, right now. Toyed with by light.
何言ってんだよ。
What are you talking about?
もっと他の、もっとかっこいいやつ、ちょっと思い出してよ。かっこいいやつ。
Think of some other, cooler ones. Remember a cool one.
やっぱこれじゃない？さっきやったこれ。あ、なるほどね。
Isn't this it? We just did this. Ah, I see.
キング！かっこいい！
King! Cool!
決まりすぎ。
Too spot on.
私かっこいいな。
I look cool.
折れとかな、折れたが。
Is it broken, broken.
あと、何もないから。
Plus, there's nothing else.
いえーい！
Yay!
だめですよ。
That's no good.
え、だって、このさ、足をやったタイミングで光がさ、かっこいい感じになったり良くない？
Eh, because, wouldn't it be cool if the light became cool right when we kick?
あっ、だって！
Ah, right!
あっ、じゃあ、せーのって、せーの！
Ah, then, on the count of—ready, set!
せーの！
Ready, set!
すごい！すごい！
Amazing! Amazing!
かっこいい！
Cool!
やばい、やばい、やばい。
No way, no way, no way.
アイドルらしい。
So idol-like.
かわいいやつ、やろ。
Let's do a cute one.
どう？
How's that?
誰？ふざけんな。
Who? Cut the crap.
おい！
Hey!
かなたんだよ！
It's Kanatan!
誰だよ！
Who is that?!
はあちゃまだって、誰だよ！
Haachama, who is that?!
おかしいでしょ！
That's weird!
どこに顔書いてんだよ！
Where did you draw the face?!
このパターンが多すぎって。
This pattern is way too much.
これははあちゃま。
This is Haachama.
はあちゃま。
Haachama.
ちょっと、あの、僕にいたずらしてませんか？
Hey, um, aren't you playing a trick on me?
なにこの、あ、これ、これ取って、これ取って食料にしよう。
What is this—ah, take this, take this and use it as food.
やめてください、取らないで！取らないで！天使の輪取らないで！
Stop it, don't take it! Don't take it! Don't take the angel's ring!
これを極秘裏に
Secretly—
やめろ！
Stop it!
極秘裏になんだ？いやこれを隠し味にするのやめろ！
Secretly what? No, stop using this as a secret ingredient!
一体どんな味するの？
What kind of taste does it even have?
あ、じゃあ自分のこれ、これ取れよ！
Ah, then take your own—take this!
これは、
This is—
いや、だめだ、これははあちゃまの生命の源だ！
No, no good, this is the source of Haachama's life!
こっちだってそうなの！はあちゃまの脳みそもちょうだいなんだから！
Mine is too! I need Haachama's brains too!
精神がなくなってきたぞ！
My sanity is fading away!
はあちゃま、これなくなったら
Haachama, if this is gone—
もう生きていけなくなっちゃうかな。
I won't be able to live anymore.
こっちだってこれ殺されていたぞ！
Mine was almost killed too!
はあちゃま！はい！
Haachama! Yes!
はいってのは
That "yes"
わけでにね、まとめられるかな、はあちゃま。
So, can we wrap it up, Haachama?
いやだ！カナタ、まとめてよ！なんでだよ、僕何も知らないぞ！
No way! Kanata, wrap it up! Why me, I don't know anything!
はい！
Yes!
このあとはね、『エンヴィベビー』を二人でね、歌いたいと思います！
After this, we'd like to sing "Envy Baby" together!
カウンクリング、引き続きかっこよくどんどんいくぞ、クールに決めていくからな！
Kauncooking, we'll keep going cooler and cooler, we'll nail it cool!
見てね！
Watch us!
見てね！カナタもクールにさ、締めましょう！
Watch us! Kanata, let's wrap it up coolly too!
じゃあクールに、えーと。
Then coolly, um.
いや、なんか不気味でちょっと怖いな、どうする？
No, it looks kind of creepy and scary, what should we do?
Hi! I wanna people save. ･･･All right?
Hi! I wanna people save. ...All right?
ジャマママママ
Jamamamama
タイトロープは 壊れる 壊される
The tightrope falls, broken by others
とんごレディ
What a lady
ライト向け 懸命に 壊れる
Towards the light, desperately shattering
そんな将来
That's her future
ハイに気ままに ロンリー ロンリー
High and without care, I'm lonely, lonely
空いた 言葉 で 弄人 囚人
From idle words, the clown becomes a prisoner
愛 も 変わらず 後悔 なんて ない
It's the same love as always, no way I'd have regrets
hey,it's a amazing.
hey, it's a amazing.
ラララ
La la la
アン レディ ディス ディス ラヴァ ベイビー
I'm ready for this this lover baby
愛 の 苑 迫り 来る 引く 手 に
My garden of love is in danger from a drawing hand
まさに ディス ディス ラヴァ クレイジー
Truly, this this lover's crazy
害 の 苑 人 の 芽 は ライアライア
In the garden of harm, the human bud is a lie-ai-a
呻吟
Ah
愛してる 過ぎ た こと まで
I love you and even things about you I shouldn't love
好き すぎる 一つ 二つ で
I love you too much, on a count of one and two
So did you say this lover crazy
骸のその
The corpse's shadow...
人の目はライアイア
People's eyes are a lie.
ああしてたら過ぎたことまで好きすぎる
Up to things that went too far if I did that,
一つ二つで
on counts of one or two,
ライライラヴィングそんな言葉でそんなことして
with such words and doing such things, lie-lie loving you.
ジャママママ
Jama mama ma
一度耐えらんない
Once unbearable love and hate,
愛憎前身泣き言重ねて
piling up forward-marching complaints.
ハイファイ恋せよライアイア
Fall in high-fi love, lie-ai-a.
演技真似て影を隠して
Mimicking acting and hiding the truth,
見つ重ねてロンリーロンリー
piling up meetings, lonely, lonely.
きっとあなたはロンリーロンリー
Surely you are lonely, lonely.
愛も変わらず後悔なんかない
Love remains unchanged, no regrets at all.
hey, it's amazing.
Ooh, let it is this lover baby
愛の巣迫り来る引く手に
Drawing hands closing in on the nest of love,
まさにディスディスラヴァクレイジー害の巣人の目はライアイア
truly this this lover's crazy, the bud in the nest of harm is a lie.
ああしてたら過ぎたことまで好きすぎる
Up to things that went too far if I did that,
一つ二つで
on counts of one or two,
ライライラヴィングそんな言葉でそんなことまで
with such words and doing such things, lie-lie loving you.
ジャママママ
Jama mama ma
ディスディスラヴァベイビー
This, this lover baby
なんたいんだよ
What is that?!
え、これ何？
Huh, what is this?
なんか揃えざるを得ない感じが
It felt like we had no choice but to match...
もうまあいいかと思って
So I just thought, "Oh well,"
これなんだよ
and what even is this?!
最後のこれなんだったの？
What was that at the end?
なんかちょっと曲がってからとりあえず飛んじゃおうと思って飛んでしまった
I twisted a bit and thought I'd just jump anyway, so I ended up jumping...
なるほどね、なるほど。青春、青春感じたわ
I see, I see. I really felt that youth vibe.
そうか、なんで青春急に我々からし、悲しみ…
Is that why? Suddenly bringing up youth from us—wait, sadness...
そう、そう青春っぽい写真撮りたいね、みんなで
Yeah, right? We want to take a youth-like photo together!
3D初めてなんだからもう少しなんか無いの？
This is our first 3D together, isn't there something more?
そうなんですよ。悲しみってもっと学友だと思ってた。
That's right. I thought "sadness" meant school friends or something.
同じようなもんだ、も学友だと思ってたから
I thought it was the same thing, like schoolmates...
悲し今日初めての3Dなんじゃ…
Wait, today is our first 3D together—
そうなんですよ！初めてなんだよ！やっとなんか揃った！
That's right! It's our first time! We finally got to match!
マネージャーさんが、悲しってなんですかって
The manager asked, "What is 'sadness'?"
え、そうなの！ちょっと待って、そうなんだよ！みんな知ってるよさすがに！
Wait, really?! Hold on, that's right! Everyone knows, of course!
まさか初めて揃うしさ、久しぶりにカラスでコラボした時
We finally matched for the first time, collaborating as Karasu after so long—
あれ？悲しってなんで漢字なの？
Huh? Why is "sadness" in kanji?
待って待って、悲しじゃなくてアッシュだから！アッシュそう、アッシュだからね！
Wait, wait, it's not "karashi," it's "Ash"! Ash, yeah, it's Ash!
ちょっとみんなに一人ずつ説明してあげて！
Explain it to everyone one by one!
アッシュはアッシュなんです！
Ash is Ash!
そうなんです、赤いハートの…
That's right, Akai Haato's...
え？違うよ？赤いハートのKで！
Eh? No way! K for Akai Haato!
K？ え、誰？アッシュどこ行った？赤いハートのKでKなんだよ！
K? Eh, who? Where did Ash go? It's K for Akai Haato!
悲しとも読めるの？ラヴァ、ラヴァ、知らぬいのラ？
Can it also be read as "karashi"? Lava, lava, Shiranui's "ra"?
ラ、ラ、星街すいせいのシ！
Ra, ra, Hoshimachi Suisei's "shi"!
エ、難しい！アッシュはAとSとHじゃん！
E, difficult! Ash is A, S, and H!
そうそうそうそう！知らぬいのラじゃん、そう、そうだ！
That's right, right! Shiranui's "ra", yeah, exactly!
ということで、みんなで青春の写真を取ろう！
With that, let's all take a youth photo!
イェーイ！これ悲し！これ悲し！写真撮りたい！
Yay! This is Karashi! This is Karashi! I want to take a picture!
会場のみんなもいいじゃん！会場の、会場の撮れるのか？
It's great for everyone at the venue too! Can the venue take pictures too?
うわー！みんな見えてるぜ！何億にいるんだこれ！
Whoa! Everyone can be seen! How many hundreds of millions are in here?!
何億、この中で何人が悲しのこと知ってるんだろ！
How many people out of these hundreds of millions know about "Karashi"?!
多分3人くらい！みんな悲しのこと知ってくれ！知ってくれ！
Probably about 3 people! Everyone, get to know Karashi! Get to know it!
これが青春の写真か！みんなと写真撮るから、ちょっとしゃがみな！
Is this a youth photo? I'm gonna take a picture with everyone, so squat down a bit!
みんな映せよ！みんな映せよ！あんたたちの自己紹介激しすぎた！
Show everyone! Show everyone! Your self-introductions were way too intense!
おい、みんな撮ってる？撮ってるね！いくよ、せーの！はーと！ハートもう一回！
Hey, is everyone taking pictures? You are! Here we go, ready, go! Heart! Heart one more time!
ハートもう一回！はーと！いいね！とれた！
Heart one more time! Heart! Nice! Got it!
だからさ、みんなね、飛ぶやつは飛ぶ。飛ぶやつはジャンプ。
So you see, everyone, those who jump, jump. Those who jump, jump.
斜めから斜めからやる。斜めから？あ、ま、漫才夫婦のキララみたいなやつ？
Do it from an angle, from an angle. From an angle? Ah, like a manzai comedy couple's Kirara?
え、違う、違う、どうした？どうした？あ、じゃこれ！これ！これ！かっこいい光と共にジャンプす。シュッ、シュッ。
Eh, no, no, what's wrong? What's wrong? Ah, then this! This! This! Jump with cool light. Shoo, shoo.
あ、なるほどね！じゃあ、いくよ、いくよ？みんな写真のやつ全部捨ててから、行くよ！
Ah, I see! Then here we go, ready? Everyone throw away all the photo stuff and let's go!
捨てないけど、行くよ？せーの！はー！
Not throwing it away, but here we go! Ready, go! Haa!
これ綺麗になんです！これうまく取れた人、ツイートしてくださいね！完璧です！完璧でした！
This turned out so clean! Whoever took a great photo, please tweet it! Perfect! It was perfect!
はい、あれちょっと待って！みんな忘れたの？はあちゃま今日誕生日だよ！
Wait a minute! Did everyone forget? Haachama's birthday is today!
誕生日だったんだ…誕生日だったの、おめでとう…
It was my birthday... It was my birthday, congratulations...
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
カラシの生誕祭かと思った
I thought it was mustard's birthday festival.
ふざけんなよ！はぁちゃまは生まれてんだわ！
Don't mess around! Haachama was born!
カラシの誕生日おめでとー！
Happy birthday, mustard!
はぁちゃまは何歳になりましたか？はぁちゃまは、えっとマイナス3歳になりました！
How old did Haachama turn? Haachama became minus 3 years old!
マイナス3歳おめでとう！ありがとー！
Happy minus 3rd birthday! Thank you!
やめて！突っ込まないで！
Stop it! Don't point that out!
今のうち！今のうち！
Now's our chance! Now's our chance!
フェードアウトしてください！
Please fade out!
あー、恋の定義がわかんない
Ah, I don't get how love's defined
まずスキって基準もわかんない
First off, what even qualifies?
要は、恋してる時が恋らしい
When love is real, it's love, it seems
客観？主観？エビデンスプリーズ！
Objective? Subjective? Evidence, please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Romance I just can’t calculate,
まず普通の計算も解けない
even regular problems are hard
要は、そんな状態が愛らしい
Romance is seemingly that state
もう大抵の事象において Q があって A を出して解けるのに
And in most cases when you get a Q there is an A to solve it
勘違いで間違うて解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
But what is this feeling that leads me to faults and misconceptions
ざわめく感情は相対性にステイ
Dazing!! Motion will relatively stay
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロディ
Turing love! Staring at one another makes it all mellow
ワットイズラブ いま 123 で証そうか
What is love? Now, on 1 2 3 proving with what we know!
言葉で生み出すクエスト (クエスト!)
Words that’ll generate a question (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
My heart’s yearning for an answer (Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらの BPM
Measurements are undetermined, that’s just our BPM
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing love! Not believing as our feet leave the ground
フォーリンラブ いまは ABC すらバグりそうだ
Fall in love! Even now ABC’s glitching into breakdown
なんとか教えてオイラー (オイラー!)
Tell your methods now, Euler (Euler!)
感想きかせてフェルマー (フェルマー!)
Tell your observation, Fermat (Fermat!)
予測不可能性 いま触れてみるんだ
Unpredictability, come let us both touch on
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう)
And so let’s show (So let’s show!)
間違いのないように
To avoid mistakes of all kinds
証明しよう (証明しよう)
So let’s show (So let’s show!)
この感情全部全部
All these feelings trapped in my mind
証明しよう (証明しよう)
So let’s show (So let’s show!)
正解があるなら
If there’s an answer for me
証明しよう (証明しよう)
So let’s show (So let’s show!)
シンプルな Q.E.D.
It’s simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! 目に見えない無理難題も ASAP!
I’ll solve it by today! This invisible, difficult problem ASAP!
三次元かっこ立体におき換えて AB間の距離を求めよ
Converting to 3D space, find the distance between A and B
好きな感じだと思ってたのに
Even though I thought it was my type
予想もかすりもし見当たらないし
My expectations didn't hit the mark at all
参考資料にも乗っていないから
It's not even in the reference materials
君と見いだして見せたいよ 三次元かっこ世界の
I want you and me to find out how to measure our feelings in this 3D world
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって君にメロバ
Turing love! Staring at one another makes it all mellow
ワットイズラブ いま 3D であかそうか
What is love? Now, on 3D proving with what we know!
言葉で生み出すクエスト ハートで高鳴るアンサー
Words that'll generate a question, my heart's yearning for an answer
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらの BPM
Measurements are undetermined, that's just our BPM
チューリングラブ 宙にまただって示さないけど
Turing love! Not believing as our feet leave the ground
ホリラブ 今はえびすシュトラブ来るそうだ
Fall in love! Even now ABC's glitching into breakdown
なんとか教えてオイラー 感想きかせてフェルマー
Tell your methods now Euler, tell your observation Fermat
予測不可能性 いま触れてみるんだ
Unpredictability, come let us both touch on
さあ証明しよう 間違いのないように
And so let's show to avoid mistakes of all kinds
証明しよう この感情全部全部
So let's show all these feelings trapped in my mind
証明しよう 正解があるなら
So let's show if there's an answer for me
証明しよう シンプルな Q.E.D.
So let's show it's simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! 目に見えない無理難題も ASAP!
I'll solve it by today! This invisible, difficult problem ASAP!
まっ、待って、えっ?
Wait, wait, what?
え、何?
Eh, what?
ねぇ、なんか最後のポーズ、え、最後、なんか合わなかったんだけど。
Hey, our final poses... wait, the very end didn't match at all!
え、でも、最後、最後、全然…え、なんて言おうって言ったっけ?
Eh, but, at the very end... wait, what did we say we were gonna do?
え、全然覚えてない、え、なに? え、なにして合わせようって言ったっけ、まじで?
Eh, I don't remember at all. What did we say to match with, seriously?
やばい、マジこの…え、マジで…
Oh no, seriously this... eh, seriously...
疲れたと思ってさ、なに、なんかさ…
I thought we were tired, so... what, like...
マジで…やばいねこれ、フリー…
Seriously... this is bad, free...
皆さん、こんにちはー!
Hello everyone!
あ、びっくりした、これ、おこおこ?
Ah, I was surprised, is this angry mode?
あ、これか。
Ah, this is it.
はーい、ということで、はじめまして、星川さーら!
Hii, so, nice to meet you, Hoshikawa Saara!
はじめまして、はーちゃまです! 今日は一緒に踊ってくれてありがとうございます!
Nice to meet you, Haachama! Thank you so much for dancing with me today!
ありがとうございます!
Thank you so much!
えーでもさ、マジでさ、やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい…
Eh, but seriously, like, oh no, oh no, oh no, oh no...
なんかさ、急にテストないで…
Like, suddenly testing us...
いや、なんか、えもいなと思って、このね、このライブのステージにね、はーちゃまが立ってるの、エモくない?
Well, I thought it was emotional, for Haachama to be standing on this live stage, isn't it?
エモいわ! みんなー、はーちゃまのステージ見えてるー?
It is emotional! Everyone, can you see Haachama's stage?
見えてるー!
We can see it!
じゃあ、写真撮ろうよ!
Then let's take a picture!
あ、いいよ!
Ah, sure!
え、なんかね、ハートもね、えーね、写真撮るんだ、写真、はーちゃまと写真撮りたいんだよね。
Eh, Hart wants to take pictures... I want to take pictures with Haachama.
え、はーちゃまやだ!
Eh, Haachama doesn't want to!
なんでだよ! 一緒に撮ろうよ! 一緒に撮ろう!
Why not! Let's take it together! Let's take it together!
いいよ、いいよ、しがまない…あ、撮ろう、撮ろう!
Okay, okay, let's not... ah, let's take it, let's take it!
いこいこ、えね、ど、まずは飛ぶやつ…あ、こっちがいい!
Let's go, first is the jumping one... ah, this one is good!
なんやねん!
What is this!
せーの! え、なになになになみ…
Ready, go! Eh, wh-wh-wh-what...
なに、ちゃんとやって、ちゃんと、ね、飛ぶの、飛ぶの! あ、いいよ、いいよ、いいよ!
What, do it properly, jump, jump! Ah, okay, okay, okay!
せーの! ほい!
Ready, go! Hoy!
え、なんか、もっとさ、寄らない? あ、ほんと? じゃあ一緒に手を繋いで…いいよ!
Eh, shouldn't we get closer? Ah, really? Then holding hands together... okay!
いくよ! せーの! うわー!
Here we go! Ready, go! Whoa!
え、みんな撮れた? 撮れた? ちゃんと。
Eh, did everyone take it? Did you take it? Properly.
もうさ、好き勝手に撮って!
Just take them however you like!
あとは、あとは…はーちゃまのとこやつ、うん。
And then, after that... Haachama's thing, yeah.
え、これ、できない? できないから…え、ここね、あ、頭のね、これを…
Eh, can't we do this? Because we can't... eh, here, ah, the head thing, this...
はーい、はーい、はーい、かわいくない? かわいい!
Hii, hii, hii, isn't it cute? Cute!
いいじゃん、いいじゃん。うえー…うぇ? え、待って、どうしちゃったの?
That's nice, that's nice. Uee... we? Eh, wait, what happened?
どうやってとじちゃった?
How did it close?
めっちゃ殴れよ、まじでよ、それ。
Punch it hard, seriously, that.
殴れよ!
Punch it!
あとは、なんか、こうやってさ、座ってさ、こう、たそがれてるみたいな感じ…
And after that, like, sitting down like this and looking wistful or something...
え、なんやろね?
Eh, I wonder what?
こういうの、毎回、ほら、やって!
Something like this, every time, look, do it!
こうやってさ…うん。
Like this... yeah.
え、なんだろう?
Eh, I wonder what?
え、なんかかわい、女の子って感じじゃない?
Eh, doesn't it feel cute, like a girl?
やばい、やばい。
Oh no, oh no.
やばい、なんかさ、ちょっとエモいなと思って。
Oh no, like, I thought it was a bit emotional.
あ、これはやばい! こういう感じのがいいな、こういう感じ。
Ah, this is bad! This kind of vibe is nice, this kind of vibe.
あらあらね、こういう感じの、やっぱ、ライブって、ライブってこういう感じだよね?
My oh my, this kind of vibe, after all, concerts are like this, right?
みんな、ありがとう、みたいな。
Like, thank you everyone.
ありがとう!
Thank you!
じゃあ、記念写真撮りまーす! はーい!
Now, we're gonna take a commemorative photo! Yay!
せーの、ハート!
Ready, go, heart!
せーの、うわ、嘘がー! うわー、すごい!
Ready, go, whoa, no way! Whoa, amazing!
はーちゃまっちゃま、ふふふ…あはっ!
Haachamatchama, fufufu... ahaha!
なんか反対! マジなんだよ、それ。
It's reversed! Seriously, what's that.
ばかにするから!
Because you're making fun of me!
今日、誕生日なんだぞ! あ、わっぴー、いわって、あー、じゃあ、今、何月?
It's my birthday today! Ah, wappy, celebrate, ah, well, what month is it right now?
えーと、じゃあ… 8月10日です!
Um, well... It's August 10th!
あ、今、8月だったの? はすかは、10月かと思ってた。8月10日だから、ちょっと誕生日祝って!
Ah, it was August right now? Hasuka thought it was October. Since it's August 10th, celebrate my birthday!
あ、そうか、プレゼントとかないの? プレゼント。はすかがプレゼント…
Ah, is that so, don't you have a present? A present. Hasuka as a present...
え、待って待って! ざけんな!
Eh, wait wait! You're kidding!
誕生日おめでとう! え、じゃあ、あれなんだよ?
Happy birthday! Eh, then, what is that?
いや、でも、確かに、ほら…
Well, but, indeed, look...
確かに、星川かがプレゼントかもしれないね。
Indeed, Hoshikawa Kawa might be a present.
そんな貯めて言うことじゃない…
That's not something to say with such suspense...
え、だって、だって、だって、あの、ほしかあと…なに?
Eh, but, but, but, um, Hoshika and... what?
覚えてる? 3Dライブやろうね、って言ってたじゃん!
Do you remember? You said, let's do a 3D live!
言ってたよ! 言ってたの? てれんのよ!
I said it! Did I say it? Don't be shy!
覚えてない、待って、照れてる感じじゃなくて、覚えてないほう、照れ…え、でもね、違うの、今日は、はすかと初めての3Dライブなんだよ!
I don't remember, wait, not that I'm shy, the part I don't remember... today is my first 3D live with Hasuka!
そうなんだよ! エモいなと思って。エモいでしょう、持ってる本当に!
That's right! I thought it was emotional. It's emotional, right, I'm really holding it!
重いよ! テンションがエモくないからさ。
It's heavy! Because the tension isn't emotional.
え、待って、初こういうの恥ずかしいでしょ、無理。
Eh, wait, my first time doing this is embarrassing, no way.
なんて、どうせ…いやだ、いやだ!
What, anyway... no way, no way!
え、待って、可愛いじゃん。あ、いいじゃん、これ、ガチコイ距離で。
Eh, wait, it's cute. Ah, this is nice, at a hardcore idol distance.
ほしかあと、ほしかあと、二人きりで…
Hoshika and, Hoshika and, just the two of us...
タイトル、タイトル! タイトル、ほしかあと二人きりの日…
Title, title! Title, just Hoshika and me on a day...
なんかさ、やって…後ろいっぱいいる!
Like, doing... there are lots of people behind us!
覚えてる? ほしかあ…急に始まった!
Do you remember? Hoshika... it started suddenly!
なに? 私たち、私たちが初めて出会った時のこと…
What? The time when we first met...
ちなみに、ほしかあは、覚えてないよ!
By the way, Hoshika doesn't remember!
ほしかあも覚えてない!
Hoshika doesn't remember either!
あ、全く何も覚えてないけど
Ah, I don't remember anything at all,
初めて会った時のことなら覚えてる
but I remember when we first met.
え、本当に？
Really?
焼肉食べた。
We ate yakiniku.
嘘つき、しゃぶしゃぶだろ！
No way, it was shabu-shabu!
違う、違う、違う違う！
No, no, no, no!
あれ、えー！
Wait, what?!
お前、待て！さっき話したばっかだろ！
Hey, wait! We just talked about this!
しゃぶしゃぶだ、しゃぶしゃぶか！
It was shabu-shabu, shabu-shabu!
しゃぶしゃぶね、しゃぶしゃぶね。
Right, shabu-shabu, shabu-shabu.
でさ、二人でさ、もうマジでなんかこうさ、何喋ればいいんだろうみたいなさ
And we were like, "What on earth are we supposed to talk about?"
いや無口な、無口な、いや無口ってか、
Well, we were silent— well, silent as in,
ピザスタじゃないの？
wasn't it pizza-sutha?
うん、そうだっけ？
Yeah, was it?
でも無言、初めはね、無言が耐えられなくてさ
And initially, neither of us could stand the silence.
「あ、なんか喋る時ある？」って思ってて、最初。気まずかったかも知れない、最初は。
Thinking, "Is there anything to say?" It might've been awkward at first.
でも今はね、一緒に、今はね、洋服買いに行く仲だ。
But now, you know, we go shopping for clothes together.
そうだよ、洋服毎回同じとこしか行かないからさ、毎回同じとこしか行ってないからさ
That's right, we always go to the exact same clothing store.
そうそう違うとことか
Right, different places—
やばい、もうそろ時間...
Oh no, it's almost time...
時間が！
Time is up!
でもさ、いつの間にか忘れて話し込んでたわ。やばい、もう時間経ったからどうしよう。
Before we knew it, we got so lost in conversation. What do we do?
はい、というわけでね。
Right, so...
はい。
Yeah.
いや、はっちゃん本当来てくれてありがとう！また今度呼んでよ！また今度呼べよ！
Haatoman, thanks for coming! Invite me again next time!
まあ気まずかったら呼びます。
Well, if it gets awkward, I will.
はい！
Yay!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
はっちゃんの応援は、はっちゃんの応援は？うん、頑張ってね、これからもね。
Haachama's support? Yeah, do your best moving forward.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
いや、カメラ映りのことしか考えてない！はっちゃん、はっちゃん！うぇーい！うぇーい！
You're only thinking about how you look on camera! Woohoo!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
はい、ここでお知らせです。
Now, here is an important announcement.
はーちゃまの3周年&誕生日記念グッズ、ついに販売します！パチパチパチパチパチパチパチ...
Haachama's 3rd anniversary and birthday goods are finally on sale!
全グッズ、まごわさび先生に描いてもらいました！いつもありがとうー！
All merchandise features brand new art by Magowasabi-sensei!
まず、こちらの3周年Tシャツ。はーちゃまの3年間の汗と涙が凝縮されております。
First up, this 3rd anniversary T-shirt with 3 years of sweat and tears.
コンセプトは「はーちゃまちゃまちゃま」。はーちゃまが二人いるというところに注目してもらいですね。このTシャツを着れば、あなたもお手軽にはーちゃまになれるよー！
Wear this T-shirt, and you can easily become Haachama too!
はい、お次はトートバッグ。はーちゃまと赤ハート様のコラボレーショングッズです。お互いの光にお互い打ち首し合ったとは思えないような、仲良しさん。
Next is the tote bag, featuring Haachama and Akai Haato.
あの日々を思い出せるようにグッズにしたいなと思ってトートバッグにしました。はーちゃまと赤ハート様が出会えた記念グッズと言っても過言ではない、そんなグッズになっております。
It's no exaggeration to call this commemorative merchandise of their meeting.
そしてそして、誕生日グッズは「足裏マウスパッド」！意外とサイズ厳しくって、いろいろ試行錯誤して、極限までエロさを引き出した、この足。マウスパッド使いながら足裏を撫でることができると。
And the birthday item is a Sole Mouse Pad, bringing out ultimate eroticism.
さらに、匂いを嗅ぐことができます。匂いには個人差がありけり。この嫌がるはーちゃまの顔がもうたまらないのよ。
What's more, you can smell it. That reluctant expression is irresistible.
隠されてる左足で妄想も捗るんじゃないの？ぜひぜひこのマウスパッドで充実したネットライフを送ってもらいたいね！
Doesn't her hidden left foot fuel your delusions? Have a fulfilling net life!
というわけで、豪華誕生日記念グッズはこの3点になります！これをフルセットで購入した先輩は、頭「はーちゃまちゃま」になれるよー！
Seniors who purchase the full set can become 'Haachamachama'!
その上、数量限定の直筆サイン入りポストカードがゲットできるかも！そもそもはーちゃまってみんなグッズ販売めったにしないから超絶激レアなのよ。
You might even get a hand-signed postcard! Haachama rarely sells goods.
だからそこのかみ、このタイミングを逃すなよ！はーちゃまのたくさん思いの込めたグッズ、ぜひぜひ買ってねー！よろしくー！ことな21時から販売だよお！
Don't miss this timing! Sales start at 21:00!
みんなー！今日は見に来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to watch today!
とっても素敵な誕生日になりました！本当に本当にありがとう！
It turned out to be such a wonderful birthday! Thank you so much!
そして、ついに最後となります。最後は、「Infinity」を歌いたいと思います。
And now, the final song will be 'Infinity'.
え、この曲はいろんな想いを込めて作った曲なので、最後までぜひ聴いてもらえると嬉しいです。
I put a lot of feelings into this, so please listen to the end.
Who am I?
Who's inside of me?
Did I ever lose my mind?
I wanna cry,
But I can't find
From where all these tears are coming down
So I'll go find the little girl
To save her from the world
To tell her "Hide no more"
A journey to the center of my heart
My heart, my heart
To find the girl who's hiding inside my heart
One for two
and two for one
I'm weak, but at least I'm not alone
I gotta run toward the sound
The voice that's calling out my name
And I'll go find the little girl
To save her from the world
To tell her "Hide no more"
A journey to the center of my heart
I'm here, eyes full of tears
Fighting all of the fears of losing you again
Dear my beloved one, my inner loneliness
Let's rewind the clock 'til we remember the happiness
You're my heart,
My heart
I am the girl who's hiding inside my heart
Hey, I'm here, eyes full of tears
Fighting all of the fears of losing you again
Dear my beloved one, my inner loneliness
Let's rewind the clock 'til we remember the happiness